O}
24 eyecatch}
Statute Books
Hanamaru Dri
Japanese
I did it!
How fun!!
How to make porridge
Hot Hot
White
Next Episode
“…The Mysterious Lifeform.”
Dobato, what’re you doing?
I’m making decorations with this pretty paper!
If I remember correctly, that paper is the manager’s…
Yes!
Chitose-san got a bunch on
sale at the shopping district,
so she asked me to make decorations for the kids at Yomogi Preschool!
I'm going to make a whole bunch of these and then decorate the walls and windows!
Do you think everyone will like them?
I think they’ll just find them annoying.
Let me tell you something.
That’s called origami.
You’re supposed to fold the paper.
Wh-What should I do, Ioryogi-san?
I can’t… I can’t fix it!
Ioryogi-san…
Of course you can’t…
…fix what you’ve cut up!
Thanks.
Sayaka-sensei.
Have you been getting enough sleep?
You look exhausted.
Hey.
You can’t tell women they look tired.
You’ll hurt their feelings.
It’s not a joke!
I’ll put these in the office.
Please.
U-Um, Sayaka-sensei.
Oh, Kobato-chan.
S-Sorry!
What’s wrong?
Um… Chitose-san wanted me to give
these to everyone in Yomogi Preschool.
Oh, origami, and so much of it!
There was even more, but…
I didn’t know origami was something you fold, so I did something else with it…
I’m so sorry!
Sayaka-sensei.
Sayaka-sensei?
Sayaka-sensei!
Fujimoto-san!
Fujimoto-san!!
What?
Sayaka-sensei is…!
I’m fine.
Let’s take you to the hospital.
There’s no way you’re fine!
Really, if I just rest for a while…
I’ll get better…
I know a doctor!
I’ll go bring him right away!
Kobato-chan!
Kobato-chan, where are you going?
Excuse me!
Excuse me, please open up!
Please open up! Excuse me!
Kobato-san?
What’s wrong?
Um, where’s Shuichiro-san?
Please help! Sayaka-sensei is…!
Please!
What’s wrong with Sayaka-sensei?
You don’t have to worry about her.
How is she?
She’s suffering from complications due to sleep-deprivation along with a mild gastritis.
I see…
I’ll give her some medicine later.
Once she gets some rest and calms down,
give her something easily digestible to eat.
Okay.
Sorry for the sudden trouble.
It’s okay.
It’s a good thing I just happened to be on vacation.
U-Um…
Will Sayaka-sensei be all right?
She won’t be just bedridden if this ever occurs again.
I wouldn’t consider this just fatigue.
Please tell her that.
Okay.
Well then, take care.
Thank you for everything.
How do you know him?
That doctor.
He’s living with Kohaku-san…
Kohaku?
Oh, that woman from before…
Yes.
What is it?
Um… Is Sayaka-sensei sick?
It’s all right.
Really?
Yeah.
The doctor said she’ll be better soon.
If you all aren’t in good spirits,
you’ll just make Sayaka-sensei worry.
Let’s all cheerfully sing so that Sayaka-sensei will get better.
Yeah!
Under the blue, under the blue,
under the big blue sky
That damn Kobato totally forgot about me.
let us feel, let us feel…
Hey.
Y-Yes?
Will Sayaka-sensei get better, if
you just sit there doing nothing?
But, just a little longer…
Get a hold of yourself already.
Looking after the children will be a better way to put her mind at ease.
That’s true.
How was it?
How’s the patient?
She’s calmed down.
I see. That’s good.
If you do this…
And then that…
Look, an angelfish!
I see, so that’s how you do origami.
Look, look, Kobato-chan!
A balloon!
Toshihiko-kun, what are you folding?
Cranes.
Cranes?
Cranes are birds.
It is a bird!
You’re folding a lot.
Yeah. A thousand cranes.
A thousand?
Yeah. To help Sayaka-sensei get better.
If you fold a thousand cranes, she’ll get better.
Toshihiko-kun.
Please, teach me how to fold cranes too!
Me too!
I’ll fold cranes too!
Then, let’s all fold them!
Like this?
Huh?
This is hard…
Like this?
Yeah, yeah.
You did it!
Will Kobato-san be all right?
Aren’t you worrying about the wrong person?
Really? Oh, right… But…
I wonder why I can't help thinking about Kobato-san.
Will Sayaka-sensei feel better tomorrow?
It’ll be all right!
We folded a thousand cranes, after all.
Yeah!
I'll try to get back from my
part-time job as soon as possible,
so take care of Sayaka-sensei in the meantime.
Yes.
Contact me immediately if anything happens.
Manager, I’ve got a request…
What now?
Could I have my work hours reduced for a while?
I thought you needed the money?
Well, that’s true, but…
...something came up.
I got it.
When you’ve got enough time again, I’ll be working you like a dog.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Sayaka-sensei.
Kobato-chan?
Have you been here this whole time?
Yes.
What about the children?
Their parents came and took them home.
I see.
Sorry for worrying you.
Get some more sleep.
I wanted to work through it all…
After you came, I’ve been
wondering in the back of my mind,
if I can trust you and Fujimoto-kun to take care of everything.
If something were to happen to me…
Why are you saying that?!
That’s… That’s…
If something were to happen to you…
Everyone… would be so sad.
So…
You shouldn’t say something like that!
Kobato-chan…
That’s enough for today. Go on home.
If you’re just going to sit around spacing out,
you’ll just give me more trouble if you end up losing sleep over this.
Spacing out?
I don’t space out!
I’ll take care of things here, so go home.
Okay.
Don’t do anything clumsy while you’re spacing out.
Like I said, I don’t-
Hurry and go.
She sure told me.
That was great on her part.
That’s true.
Kobato-chan was right to say that.
The children folded all of these.
Yes.
These are the cranes she folded.
They all have the same flaws.
She really is a good girl.
Are you that worried about Sayaka?
Hey, Kobato.
No, nevermind.
Okay…
Could her memories be coming back?
Chiho-chan, what’s the answer to #7?
Chise-chan, you don’t know?
Kobato-san!
It’s Kobato-san!
Um, is Chitose-san here?
Mama’s at the neighborhood association meeting.
I see.
What’s wrong?
Kobato-san, you don’t look well.
Actually...
...it’s an illness!
Oh no, Kobato-san!
Not me…!
Sayaka-sensei is ill!
I want to do something for
Sayaka-sensei, but I don’t know what.
I folded a thousand cranes with everyone, but…
Thousand cranes?
Yes…
But I couldn’t fold them well…
What if the wish doesn’t come
true because of my bad folding?
It’ll be all right, Kobato-san.
Your wish will surely come true!
I hope so…
What about that?
Remember what Mama would
always make us when we were sick?
Porridge?
Yeah, porridge!
Oh, porridge!
Mama told us that porridge is easy to
digest, so it’s good to eat when you’re sick!
Easy to digest?
Now that I think about it,
Shuichiro-san said that too…
“Give her something easily digestible to eat,” he said.
Then Kobato-san, how about
you make some porridge for her?
Yeah, Sayaka-sensei will definitely get better, then!
Yes!
I’ll make porridge for Sayaka-sensei!
But how do I make it?
I know, Chiho-chan! How about you draw her a picture of it?
Nice idea, Chise-chan!
It looks something like this…
This is porridge?
It’s white…
And it’s kind of thick and syrupy.
That’s right! Thick… and… syrupy.
And when we eat it, Mama tells us to be careful not to burn our tongues.
Hot… hot…
And when you make it, put lots of water in!
Soaked… in… water.
This looks amazing!
Is that really going to work?
Who’s there?
What are you doing?
I was trying to make porridge.
Even though Chiho-chan and
Chise-chan taught me how to make it…
I can’t make it well…
Porridge is supposed to be easy to digest.
That’s why I wanted to make some for Sayaka-sensei.
You put in rice and plenty of water,
put it on the stove and wait for it to boil.
Afterwards, you just let it cook on low heat.
For crying out loud, how did you make that thing?
If you let her eat that, you’d
just make her even more sick.
H-Hey, don’t cry.
If Sayaka-sensei dies…
She’ll be fine.
People don’t die that easily.
They could die!
People can die from the littlest things.
Like who?
It’s all right.
Sayaka-sensei won’t die.
It’s all right…
It’s delicious!
This’ll give me 100% energy!
That’s great.
I might eat too much.
So good!
I’m glad I could help!
Well, I was the one who made pretty much all of it.
Y-Yeah, but…
But what?
Nothing.
Thought so.
You didn’t even get more.
The confetti won’t increase
if you just keep staring at it.
Yes!
You don’t seem depressed about it.
Now that you mention it…
I wonder why.
Back then, after crying in front of Fujimoto-san,
it felt like a lot of things that had been
building up inside me were unwrapped…
And it felt really warm.
Why are you getting healed when
you’re supposed to be doing the healing?
Healed?
This is…?
Good morning.
Good morning!
It’s Sayaka-sensei!
Good morning.
Sayaka-sensei, good morning!
Sensei, are you feeling better?
I’m fine now.
Did our thousand cranes work?
Kobato-chan, good morning!
Yes, good morning!